ALEX KHOMUTOV

+1 (929) 722-5624 alex@khomutov.me khomutov.me

HIGHLIGHTS

In the recent **5 years**, I have been focusing on designing iOS, iPadOS, macOS, and Web apps. My passion is creating products that make people more organized and productive. So far, I have designed products that are used by more than **30,000,000** people around the world.

AWARDS

Red Dot Design Award, 2021 Calendars by Readdle, Mobile App

The Very Best of Apps Design, 2021 Smartist, Mobile App

SKILLS

Design

Interaction Design, Visual Design, Prototyping, Sketching, User flows, Storyboarding.

Research

Competitor analysis, User research, User Interviews, Surveys, Usability testings.

Tools

Figma, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, After Effects, Principle, Marvel, Lookback, and many more.

EXPERIENCE

Double, Sr. Product Designer

Aug 2021 – Present • Los Angeles, California • Full-time

- I'm leading the design of the Double App for Web, and iOS;
- Conduct user research, including surveys, user interviews, and usability testing to understand customer needs and preferences and use insights to inform design decisions;
- Facilitate design reviews and brainstorming sessions for the entire team to get feedback and generate effective solutions for product challenges;
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams, including engineers, marketers, customer success, and operations, to bring product vision to life.

Smartist, Sr. Product Designer

Oct 2019 - Jul 2021 • Odesa, Ukraine • Part-time

- Led the design of the <u>Smartist App</u>, from the idea, competitor analysis, market and user research, user flows, prototyping, user testing, and to visual and interaction design;
- Played a critical role in product strategy, design vision, technology choice, recruiting & hiring, and launch preparation.

Readdle, Sr. Product Designer

Dec 2018 – Jul 2021 • Odesa, Ukraine • Full-time

- Redesigned one of the most popular calendar apps on iOS with millions of active users — <u>Calendars by Readdle</u>, resulting in a 255% increase in revenue, a 145% increase in downloads, and a 157% increase in MAU;
- Redesigned <u>Scanner Pro 8</u>, recognized as the best scanning app by the New York Times, with a notable increase in revenue and 10x in downloads;
- Utilized data-driven insights to inform design choices, achieve measurable business results, and fulfill users' needs.

DataArt, UX & UI Designer

Aug 2017 - Nov 2018 • Kyiv, Ukraine • Full-time

- Designed web systems for the healthcare industry;
- · Created data visualizations for a variety of projects and platforms;
- Collaborated with the design team, project managers, and medical employees, including doctors and company's stakeholders.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Fine and Applied Arts

Rivne State University of Humanities

Sep 2012 - Jul 2017 • Rivne, Ukraine

Studied painting, drawing, composition, color theory, typography, and computer graphics.